<Publish>
  <!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
  <ModId Value="75993" />
  <!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
  <DisplayName Value="Tree Controller" />
  <!--Short description of the mod-->
  <ShortDescription Value="Plop selected age tree. Change Age and Type of trees and bushes. Forest brushes. Optional custom seasonal colors, dead model in winter, and disable tree growth." />
  <!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
  <LongDescription>Tools and systems for changing ages, types, colors, growth seasonal, and wind behaviors for trees, bushes, and plants. Forest brushes.

Video Demo available on YouTube.

# Dependencies
Unified Icon Library

I18n Everywhere (Soft dependency required for loading languages other than English.)

## Donations
If you want to say thank you with a donation you can do so on Paypal.

## Translations
I am looking for volunteers to help translate the mod into the official languages. For those interested please find the project in the crowdin or discord link. CSL2:CODEMODS -&gt; mods-wip -&gt; Tree Controller: Translations.
Fully or Partially Supported Languages: German, Spanish, Italian, Brazilian Portuguese, Chinese Simplified, Polish, French, Japanese, Korean, Russian, Chinese Traditional and European Portuguese.

## Supplemental Mods
European Portuguese Localization (Only needed for European Portuguese Translations)

# Detailed Description:
Includes a tree controller tool that lets you change the age or types of existing trees and/or bushes on the following selections:
* Single Tree
* Whole Building or Net
* Radius
* Whole Map

Please don't use my tools to change street trees, use the new vanilla option.

For brushing vegetation this mod has sets of vegetation for forest brushes. Some pre-made sets are:
* Deciduous (Exluding Apple and Poplar)
* Evergreen (Pine and Spruce)
* Wild bushes 

Settings button to remove all trees and plants that are not part of a road, building, park, etc. Intended for those that want to start a new map but redo the trees and bushes themselves. (Contributed by phillycheeze)

Tree Wind Controller options in the Wind settings tab. Can Disable or Override shader values for how wind affects trees and vegetation.

This mod allows you to select tree ages while plopping objects with tree subobjects such as buildings and round-a-bouts.

Dead and Stump (optional default off) are added to age selection when applicable. These do not work for street tree placement.

Option for Free Trees and Vegetation (sets prices to 0) (Default Off).

Option to constrain the brush while placing multiple trees and vegetation. (Default On).

Adds new random seeds to tree subojects inside a building will no longer have exactly same colors and their ages can be randomized.

Option for Faster Max Brush Strenth which replaces 100% with 300%. (Default off).

Option for Limited Tree Anarchy where conflict checks approximately based on trunk instead of drip line. (Default off). Be careful with this if settings are reset. But you can bring them back with Anarchy component tool if something disappears from being overriden.

## Custom sets
Hold Ctrl to select or unselect multiple types of trees using the toolbar menu. Then hold Ctrl and click the custom set button to save a custom set. Once a set has been saved, click the custom set button to select that set. Hold Ctrl while switching themes to maintain the custom set.

Press the gear button to open the Advanced Set Control Panel that lets you set Age overrides, Probability weights, and minimum and maximum elevations for each prefab in a set. Age overrides and Probability weights work with object tool and line tools. Minimum and maximum elevations are only for brushing objects. 

## Tree Growth
Includes the option to disable tree growth over the whole map but it excludes any trees within specialized lumber industry areas.

To set all trees to Adult and/or Elderly, Select: Landscaping -&gt; Vegetation -&gt; Change Age Tool -&gt; Whole Map -&gt; Select Age(s) -&gt; Right click on the map. 

This mod doesn't automatically set street trees or trees in buildings to a specified age, but you can change them with the tool. This feature may be included later.

## Seasonal Effects
Includes the option to make deciduous trees use dead model during winter. The dead model is not scaled based on the actual age of the tree.
Deciduous tree growth is paused during winter. Specialized lumber industry areas are excluded from this feature.

Please note, you must either disable this option or press the 'Safely Remove Button' to remove the mod safely during winter.
During any other season the mod can be readily removed. If you do not enable this option the mod can be readily removed.

The mod has sets of seasonal color variations for trees and plants including a curated set by me and year round spring and autumn colors.
Custom color variations set has been removed and will be replaced soon in a new mod called Recolor.

## Collaboration
Algernon and I have collaborated to allow for sets and multiple vegetation types selection using Line Tool.

# Support
I will respond on the code modding channels on Cities: Skylines Modding Discord.

# Credits 
* yenyang - Mod Author
* Chameleon TBN - Testing, Feedback, Icons, and Logo
* BruceyBoy - Co-Authored Tree Wind Controller
* phillycheese - Code Contribution
* donutmonger - Original author of Tree Wind Controller on Thunderstore.
* Algernon - Help with UI, Cooperative Development and Code Sharing, Collaboration regarding line tool.
* Klyte45 - Help with UI, Cooperative Development and Code Sharing
* T.D.W., krzychu124, and Quboid - Cooperative Development and Code Sharing
* Nullpinter - Localization support
* Localization: Hendrix and Fuchs23 (German), Nyoko and Citadino (Spanish), Mazi and Furios (Italian), Luiz Fernando de Paula and felipecollucci (Brazilian Portuguese), RilkeXS and Nullpinter (Chinese Simplified), karmel68 (Polish), Karg, edouardtherrien24, CEO of Tabarnak, Morgan (French), syuuga101 (Japanese), TwotoolusFLY_LSh.st (Korean), _hayrynenart and SivenesisI (Russian), allegretic (Chinese Traditional), Ti4goc (European Portuguese), 
* Tigon Ologdring, code:witch - Testing, Feedback</LongDescription>
  <!--Thumbnail-->
  <Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
  <!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/treeControllerToolScreenshot.jpg" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/fall2.jpg" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/spring.jpg" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/summer.jpg" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/fallApple.jpg" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/winter.jpg" />
  <!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
  <Tag Value="Code Mod" />
  <!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
  <ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/tree-controller.1644992/" />
  <!--Version of the mod-->
  <ModVersion Value="1.6.0" />
  <!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
  <GameVersion Value="1.2.*" />
  <!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
  <Dependency Id="74417" DisplayName="Unified Icon Library" Version="1.0.11" />
  <Dependency Id="75426" DisplayName="I18n EveryWhere" Version="1.3.3" />
  <!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
  <ChangeLog># Patch v1.6.0
* Added ability to select tree ages while plopping objects with tree subobjects such as buildings and round-a-bouts.
* Added Dead trees back to age selection with object tool, vanilla and modded line tool. (Does not work with street tree placement).
* Added Free Trees and Vegetation option. (Default Off)
* Added option to add Stumps to age selection with object tool, vanilla and modded line tool, and tree changing tools. (Default Off) (Does not work with street trees placement).
* Added option to constrain brush while adding trees and vegetation with object tool brush mode. (Default On).
* Age randomization is now tied to RandomSeeds and behaves more like current vanilla than old versions of Tree Controller.
* Added new random seeds to tree subobjects so trees inside a building will no longer have exactly same colors and their ages can be randomized.
* Added option for Faster Max Brush strength (default off).
* Added Limited Tree Anarchy option. Conflict checks approximately based on trunk instead of drip line. (default off). Be careful with this if settings are reset. But you can bring them back with Anarchy component tool if something disappears from being overriden.
* Added Advanced Set Control Panel that lets you set Age overrides, Probability weights, and minimum and maximum elevations for each prefab in a set. Age overrides and Probability weights work with object tool and line tools. Minimum and maximum elevations are only for brushing objects. 
* Sets can also be selected with single object placement.</ChangeLog>
  <!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon-->
  <ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/HTav7ARPs2" />
  <ExternalLink Type="paypal" Url="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/YenyangsMods" />
  <ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/yenyang/Tree_Controller" />
  <ExternalLink Type="youtube" Url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YoyMliyWJQU" />
  <ExternalLink Type="crowdin" Url="https://crowdin.com/project/csl2-mod-water-features" />
</Publish>